[MUSIC PLAYING]
安全就像汽车保险
ADDY: Security is a lot like car insurance.
大部分人都不会想买
Most people don't want to pay for it.
我同意
MATT: I agree with that.
一些人就是不会去买它
ADDY: Some people don't pay for it.
所以这里有一个问题
MATT: So here's the thing.
对我而言  我不介意在汽车保险上花钱
For me, I don't mind paying for car insurance
因为万一我弄坏了我的车
because it means that if I destroy my car,
或者我的车被偷了  我就能获得赔偿
or it gets stolen, you get your money back.
这能减少我的损失
And then it's fine.
这其实算是一种投资
It's sort of an investment.
我不喜欢它的地方是
The thing that I don't like about it
在办理过程中他们会发份法律文件给你
is, I'm not going to read the massive 50-page long legal
一份长达 50 页长篇大论式的法律文件  我可不打算去读它
document they send you in the process of getting said car insurance.
当事情发生了我可以获得赔偿
I'm fine with it happening, the payment going out to get it.
做这么多事就是为了这个
It's everything around it.
我从来没读过那些合同
ADDY: I never read those agreements.
我甚至没读过 iTunes 的许可协议
I'm not even committed enough to read the iTunes license agreement.
是的  这和我为我的网站做的一些安全工作
MATT: And yeah, that's basically exactly the same thing
基本是同一个情况
as I've done for my site.
SSL 的目的就是为了保证用户的安全
The whole point of SSL is to keep users secure.
而 Service Worker 的存在也是有它的意义的
And Service Worker, it does actually make a lot of sense.
因为你会需要一些东西在后台
Because you're going to have something controlling
控制你的页面
your page in the background.
如果有人能侵入到这中间
And if someone can get in the middle,
然后替换掉 Service Worker
and then swap out Service Worker,
比如让 addyosmani.com/blog 指向我的网站  我的博客文章
like addyosmani.com/blog could go straight to my site, my blog posts.
啥
ADDY: What?
我可以窃取你所有的广告收入
MATT: I could steal all your ad revenue.
如果真这样的话我觉得是
ADDY: If anything, it would probably
对内容质量的一次改进
be an improvement in content quality.
开玩笑的
MATT: Not true.
但是我知道出现这种情况的根本原因
But I can understand the main point of it.
之所以出现这些问题原因在于
The problem I have with all of this
学习 SSL 真是太难了
is it's really hard to learn about SSL.
首先  许多资料都蛮旧的了
A, there's tons of old content.
你可以通过他们了解如何为你的网站配置 SSL
This is how you set up SSL on your site.
虽然有用  不过太旧了
It's useful, but it's old.
其次  影响整件事结果的因素
And then secondly, there were so many different factors
太复杂了
to the whole thing.
所以当我试着为我的网站配置它的时候
ADDY: So when I was trying to set this stuff up on my site--
我甚至没有将 HTTPS 设置为默认
and I don't even default to HTTPS just yet, because there's
因为我还是不知道怎么处理
still-- I still don't know how to handle all the mixed content
那些来自我加载的第三方模块的安全警示
security warnings I'm getting from the third parties
比如一些小部件  还有分享按钮等等
I'm loading, like widgets, and share buttons, and from.
没错
MATT: Yeah.
感觉这一切对我来说
ADDY: And it's like all the tooling around this
就像是一片雷区
is sort of a minefield to me.
我发现我很难找到方向
I find it hard to navigate those waters.
我也确实  我已经反复在我的网站上
MATT: So I've literally-- I've done numerous steps
配置过很多次了  但即使是这样  我还是会遇到问题
into how I got it on my site, and even then, I've got issues.
所以第一个我要说的是 SSL labs
So the first one was SSL labs.
你只管给它一个 URL
You just bung in your URL.
然后它就会去查看你的网站
And it will look at your site and figure out
检查 HTTP 是否会重定向到 HTTPS
whether HTTP redirects to HTTPS, and just
还能看到你网站的 HTTPS 的配置
the configuration of HTTPS on your site.
所以如果我在 SSL labs 里输入 gauntface.com
So if I bung in gauntface.com in SSL labs, I was, at one point,
我曾经很荣幸拿到过一个 A+ 的评价  我当时挺开心的
getting a glorious A-plus, which I was very happy about,
然而现在我只拿到了 C
and now I've been downgraded to a C.
你的网站改了很多吗
ADDY: Have you changed your site a lot?
MATT: 不
MATT: No.
又或者是
So-- ADDY: Is there a way of--
其实是因为发现了 POODLE 漏洞
MATT: So what's happened is there was the POODLE vulnerability.
我想这多半是由于 SSL3
And I think that's basically all through SSL3.
而且我仍然在我的网站上  我知道了
And I've still got SSL3 support-- ADDY: Oh, I see.
使用 SSL3
MATT: --on my site.
所以即使在其他方面做的很不错
So even though everything is actually doing really well,
比如在每一个顶层项目上都拿到了 100 或是 90 的高分
like 190's for the scores on each top-level topic,
介于 SSL3 和 POODLE 漏洞他们还是只能给我 C
they've kept me to a C because of SSL3 and POODLE.
他们能够保证你的网站跟得上时代  这点很不错
ADDY: I guess it's cool that they're keeping it up to date.
是的  你可以时常在上面
MATT: Yeah, so this is the nice thing,
测试你的网站
is you can keep on regularly running through this,
保证你的网站跟得上时代并且追踪潜在的问题
and will keep it up to date and track everything.
另一个好处在于
The really nice thing with this is it's really good.
它包括了非常多的信息  都有点太多了
It's a ton of information, possibly too much.
但是在这时候  比如说协议  就像这样
But at the same time, things like protocols, it's saying,
你支持 SSL2 吗
do you support SSL2?
不
No.
你支持 SSL3 吗
Do you support SSL3?
是的
Yes.
这不安全
It's insecure.
这些是你使用的 cipher suite
These are the cipher suites that you have.
然后它应该  如果发现有什么问题
And it literally-- if there's one particular thing that
比如说发现不好的实现  它就该将它标注出来
is, like, this is actually really a bad practice, it highlights it.
这样你起码可以去 Google 一下解决方法
And then you can at least go and Google and find out the problem.
所以这里是我发现的第一个解决方法
So this was the first thing that I found.
我在很多方面都不在行
I was like, sweet, these are all the places
总的说做的很烂  好吧我认了
that I suck, and overall I'm doing bad, well, or whatever.
不过之后我发现 Mozilla SSL
The best thing I found after this was the Mozilla SSL
配置生成器
configuration generator.
简直是个神器
And this thing is a godsend.
它替你把这些事都做了吗
ADDY: Does it do all the work for you?
是的  太棒了
MATT: Yes, so good.
我遇到的其中一个问题是
So basically, one of the issues that I had was,
我怎么知道怎样的 SSL cipher suite 才算好
how do I know what a good SSL cipher suite is?
SSL labs 会告诉你是好是坏
And SSL labs tells you good or bad.
但是它却不会告诉你
The problem is, it doesn't necessarily
你该怎么进行配置
tell you the right names to put in your configuration file.
使用 Mozilla SSL 配置生成器
Enter a Mozilla SSL Config Generator.
你可以选择服务器是 Apache 或者 Nginx
So you can select, like, Apache or Nginx.
你可以选择想要支持哪些浏览器
You can select what sort of browser support you want.
这样你可以很直接的处理一些情况
So you can be really harsh and be
比如  如果有个很旧的浏览器它需要运行一些东西
like, if there's an old browser that requires xyz to work,
你就可以简单的说  抱歉
you can just basically say, sorry, I'm
介于安全原因  这个功能不被支持或是其他什么的
not going to support that for security reasons or whatever else.
你可以直接使用它获取配置文件
And it literally just gives you the config file,
所有都已经配置好了
everything just set up.
这太好了
ADDY: That's awesome.
之后我也检查了下 SSL 配置中确实不包含 SSL3
MATT: So I'm looking at it, and already the SSL protocols
这避免了 POODLE 漏洞
doesn't include SSL3, which is why I'm now susceptible to POODLE.
我只要复制这份配置
So all I have to do is literally copy this back over,
一切都搞定了
and I'm good to go.
然后最近  就在上周还是什么时候
Then, very recently, the past week or so,
有人向我介绍了 httpsecurityreport.com
someone introduced me to httpsecurityreport.com.
httpsecurityreport.com 好吧
ADDY: httpsecurityreport.com, OK.
这是干什么的
What does it do?
这其实和 SSL labs 很像
MATT: So, it literally is very similar to SSL labs.
它做的很不错  你可以从
It's kind of nice because it gives you
更高层次总览你的网站上
an even higher level of overview of where
做的好的部分
you're doing well on your site.
但是它还关注了一些不同的东西
But this looks at slightly different things.
比如  我从来没有考虑过网站的内容安全策略
Like, I've never considered the content security policy
这个东西就是说
of my site, which is things like,
如果你引入了第三方资源
if you're pulling in a third-party resources,
比如 Google Fonts
like Google Fonts, you can basically say,
并且你的 CSP 策略中不包含它  这样即使你在页面中调用了它
if I have a CSP policy which excludes that, it won't load,
它也不会被加载
even though I called it in on my web page.
所以如果你的页面混杂了许多内容
So with your mixed-content thing,
你可以坐下说 CSP 只包含 addyosmani.com
you could sit there and say, CSP is just addyosmani.com.
这样除了它之外的资源都不会加载
That would all just get shut down.
这样可能不是你想要的结果  但是有趣的地方是
Which is not what you want, but it's an interesting point
在没有使用过这种工具之前这些东西都不会引起我的重视
that I've never even considered as a thing until I used this tool.
这工具不错
ADDY: This tool is neat.
目前我的网站默认是非 HTTPS 版本的
The current default non-HTTPS version of my site
100 分里确实只能拿到 17 分
is getting a very, very respectable 17 out of 100 at the moment.
是的
MATT: That's good.
很不错
ADDY: It's great.
其实我一猜就猜到是这个分数了
MATT: I'm guessing 17 out of 100, rather than 20, just saying.
让我们继续
ADDY: Let's go with that.
而 HTTPS 版本能拿到个整整 51 分
And the HTTPS version is getting a solid 51.
漂亮
MATT: Nice.
还不算太糟
That's not too bad.
我只有 62
I'm only on 62.
所以我还要继续改进
So I've got some work to do.
但是有趣的地方是
But the interesting thing with this
它能准确的捕获如 web 框架这样的信息
is it actually picks up things like web framework information.
这就是说如果你使用 PHP
And that's things like, oh, PHP is actually
它会告诉你支持的 PHP 版本
saying this is the version of PHP
或者你正在使用某个引擎的某个版本
you support, or you're actually on version x of engine x.
同样的  我还是没有想过去仔细看
Which, again, I wouldn't have ever thought
因为在我的脑子里
of looking into because in my head,
我跟本没想过这类工具
I wouldn't expect those tools to be sharing
默认会透露这些信息
that kind of information by default, let alone
就这样放任这些安全隐患不管
it be a security issue anyway.
但是这三样东西我发现非常有用
But those three things, I found immensely helpful.
我通常使用它们来指导我进行
I'm using them basically to guide where I spend
下一步的工作
all my time and effort on work.
听上去不错
ADDY: Sounds good.
[MUSIC PLAYING]